Kunal**Chandan**

Computer Engineering Student

About

kunalthechandan@ -gmail.com kunalchandan.github.io Cell: (647)-785-1313

Interests

I take heavy interest in computer science, mainly in statistical analysis and machine learning. I first learned to program with Java in 2015, since then I have been improving my skills now I have some experience with Keras, Octave, and OpenCV.

Languages

Bilingual English & Hindi Professional French

Programming

Java LWJGL-Python OpenCV-Octave/MATLAB PsychToolbox-HTML & JavaScript LaTeX

Education

2018–2023 **Expected Computer Engineering Degree** University of Waterloo Honours Computer Engineering Co-op. Starting September of 2018

2014–2018 Ontario Secondary School Diploma Northview Heights Secondary School

Specialist High Skills Major; Information Computer Tech. (SHSM - ICT) Honours in Math, Science and Technology (HMST)
Jim McQueen Award for Excellence in Education

Experience

2017-2018 Elder Lab, York University Research Internship.

Computer Vision, Machine Learning, and Psychophysics

-Learning to design neural networks for application i.e. Traffic tracking -Creating psychophysics experiments using MATLAB with PsychToolbox

-Data augmentation, visualization, interpretation using Python, OpenCV, MatPlotLib

-Designing methods to gather Mechanical Turk data

2017 Camp NAORCA, City of Toronto Camp Counsellor.

Voted Rookie of the year; outdoor youth summer camp

2017-2018 FIRST Team 6632, Supreme Robotics Build Executive

Lead and coordinated Supreme Robotics' build team

2018 Northview Heights Secondary School Lead Programming Mentor

Mentored Northview's Co-Ed and All-girls programming teams

2016-2018 Private Tutoring Math & Science Tutor

Tutored children in math and science at local libraries.

Projects

2017-Curr. Github github.com/kunalchandan

Personal programming projects, highlights include:

-Game Engine written from scratch using OpenGL Java bindings (LWJGL)

-Multi-expression Command Line Calculator

-Solutions to programming contests

-Resume Written in LaTeX

2017-Curr. Personal Website kunalchandan.github.io kunalchandan.github.io

Various JavaScript applets, web-toys, and 3D Modeling/Rendering

2017–Curr. Psychophysics Experiments Research internship related work

Designed and implemented psychophysics experiments similar to current research in the

Elder Lab to test propogation of visual information in the brain.

Other Extra-Curriculars

2014–2018 Academic Clubs

-Programming Club Founder -Biology Club Executive -Physics Club Member -Math Team Member -DECA Chapter Executive -SHSM-ICT President

-FIRST Robotics Build Executive

2014–Curr. Sports Clubs

-Cross Country Coach/Member

-Badminton Member -Water Polo Member

-Track & Field Coach/Member

Awards

2014–2018 Academic Awards

-Jim McQueen Award for Excellence in Education

-Co-op Award for Outstanding Achievement - Grade 12

-Business Award - Grade 9 & 10

-Honour Roll - All Semesters

-University of Toronto National Biology Competition Scholar Award - Grade 12

-CCC Junior 1st place Northview - Grade 11

-ECOO Round 2 Finalist - Grade 11

-Toronto Finalist for Office Skills Competition - Grade 10

-Toronto Finalist for Robotics and Control Systems - Grade 11

2014–2018 Athletic Awards

-Bronze Medallion for TDSSAA - Cross Country -Silver Medallion for TDSSAA - Track & Field